Ryan Skeans

(951) 234-1872 | ryanskeans@gmail.com | San Diego, CA

Summary

Software Engineer with experience in Typescript, css, and various frameworks. Proven success developing and deploying software solutions. Experienced in agile methodologies, code refactoring, bug fixing, and code development. I am excited to continue expanding and enhancing my skillset as part of an excellent team.

Experience

SS&C Advent | San Francisco, CA Software Engineer | 02/2022 - Present

- Integrated both REST and GraphQL API's into our application to create data rich experiences.
- Wrote tests and collaborated with QA/QE teams to ensure a high quality user experience at all times.
- Developed a wide range of UI components ranging from buttons and dropdowns, all the way to entirely new screens.
- Utilized a modern tech stack including Sass, React, Typescript, Cypress, Web Components, GraphQL, and REST.
- Collaborated with backend developers to implement front-end functionalities for complex web applications, ensuring seamless integration of UI components with backend services.
- Contributed to the company-wide design system that demanded components be powerful, but also highly reusable.
- Leveraged a Javascript data visualization framework to create dynamic, data driven SVG charts.
- Employed CSS variables to extend a maintainable front end platform.
- Optimized website performance by regularly refactoring to newer web technologies and trimming down on bloat.
- Utilized tools like Jenkins, Github Actions, and Docker images to get work done efficiently and quickly.

Prudential Financial | San Francisco, CA Senior Product Management Associate | 07/2020 - 02/2022

- Worked to build and enhance Prudential's retail/direct to consumer products
- · Analyzed and provided insights on KPI's using Tableau and Adobe Analytics
- Participated in design sprints aimed at providing the customer with the best experience possible
- Helped unblock and guide user stories to completion in an agile workplace

Prudential Financial | Sunnyvale, CA Product Management Intern | 06/2019 - 08/2019

- Worked collaboratively with UX, UI, and backend engineers to develop intuitive workflows based on competitive research
- · Helped review, summarize, and distribute results from multiple rounds of user testing for our product
- Created low fidelity wire frames and coordinated with UX teams to refine based on industry best practices

Education

California Polytechnic State University | San Luis Obispo, CA B.S. Business Administration, Financial Management | 06/2020

Top Skills

React, Web Components, Typescript, JavaScript, Node.js, HTML, SQL, Express.js, Webpack, Material, CSS, Git, GitHub, Cypress, NPM, Node.js, Python, SASS, Python, REST API's, Web Services, Swift

Websites

Github: https://skeanster.github.io/

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ryanskeans/

Personal Website: https://skeanster.github.io/